{
  "reference_number": "11919",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "NZ has almost no carbon foot print in global scale why make people's life miserable and more expensive? Our climate here is not as\n\n bad as The USA, China or India. These targets should be for them not us."
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Again NZ has almost no carbon foot print in global scale why make people's life miserable and more expensive? Our climate here is\n not as bad as The USA, China or India. These targets should be for them not us."
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Again NZ has almost no carbon foot print in global scale why make people's life miserable and more expensive? Our climate here is\n not as bad as The USA, China or India. These targets should be for them not us."
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "NZ has almost no carbon foot print in global scale why make people's life miserable and more expensive? Our climate here is not as\n\n bad as The USA, China or India. These targets should be for them not us."
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The Government proposes that three emissions budgets of five years each (i.e. covering the next 15 years) be in place at any given time. Do you agree with this proposal?",
      "question_index": 15,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "NZ has almost no carbon foot print in global scale why make people's life miserable and more expensive? Our climate here is not as\n bad as The USA, China or India. These targets should be for them not us."
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Should the Government be able to alter the last emissions budget (i.e. furthest into the future)?",
      "question_index": 4,
      "answer": "Yes - each incoming Government should have the option to review the third budget in the sequence",
      "answer_index": 14,
      "notes": "NZ has almost no carbon foot print in global scale why make people's life miserable and more expensive? Our climate here is not as\n\n bad as The USA, China or India. These targets should be for them not us."
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Should the Government have the ability to review and adjust the second emissions budget within a specific range under exceptional circumstances? See p36 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 5,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "NZ has almost no carbon foot print in global scale why make people's life miserable and more expensive? Our climate here is not as\n\n bad as The USA, China or India. These targets should be for them not us."
    },
    {
      "question": "8. Do you agree with the considerations we propose that the Government and the Climate Change Commission take into account when advising on and setting budgets? See p44 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 6,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "NZ has almost no carbon foot print in global scale why make people's life miserable and more expensive? Our climate here is not as\nbad as The USA, China or India. These targets should be for them not us."
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "NZ has almost no carbon foot print in global scale why make people's life miserable and more expensive? Our climate here is not as\n\nbad as The USA, China or India. These targets should be for them not us."
    },
    {
      "question": "10. What are the most important issues for the Government to consider in setting plans to meet budgets? For example, who do we need to work with, what else needs to be considered?",
      "question_index": 8,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "What are actually the polluters ( USA China India etc) doing at the same time? Consider Economy, people's living standards, our\ncarbon foot print on global scale and its cost to us as tax payers."
    },
    {
      "question": "11. The Government has proposed that the Climate Change Commission advises on and monitors New Zealand's progress towards its goals. Do you agree with these functions? See p42 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 9,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "No need to waste money on this yet. Polluters should actually pay for this not a clean country like NZ. without doing anything we\n\nwould still be cleaner than those."
    },
    {
      "question": "12. What role do you think the Climate Change Commission should have in relation to the New Zealand Emissions Trading Scheme (NZ ETS)?",
      "question_index": 10,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "No need to waste money on this yet. Polluters should actually pay for this not a clean country like NZ. without doing anything we\nwould still be cleaner than those."
    },
    {
      "question": "13. The Government has proposed that Climate Change Commissioners need to have a range of essential and desirable expertise. Do you agree with the proposed expertise? See p45 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 11,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "No need to waste money on this yet. Polluters should actually pay for this not a clean country like NZ. without doing anything we\n\nwould still be cleaner than those."
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "Tiny NZ is not even important freaking tree hugers."
    },
    {
      "question": "15. The Government has proposed a number of new functions to help us adapt to climate change. Do you agree with the proposed functions? See p47 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 13,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "16. Should we explore setting up a targeted adaptation reporting power that could see some organisations share information on their exposure to climate change risks?",
      "question_index": 14,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you have any other comments you'd like to make?",
      "question_index": 16,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "I know you tree hugers think you are important and doing something great, you should go after global polluters and stop countries\nlike USA who didn't even sign the treaty or accept global warming. You are wasting people's time and money here in NZ on your\n\nstupid ambitious and idiotic ideas. This money could be use to fight poverty, warm houses and provide better health services to\npeople."
    }
  ]
}
